David Von Drehle Papers
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
David Von Drehle Papers 1897-2003
nam_apap213
7.5 cubic ft.
Von Drehle, David, 1961-
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The David Von Drehle Papers contain information on the death penalty, primarily in Florida. Von Drehle compiled the materials while researching his 1995 book Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
David Von Drehle donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections at the State University of New York, Albany in 2005 and 2007.
Biographical Sketch
David Von Drehle was born in Denver, Colorado on February 6, 1961; he now resides in Shawnee Mission, Kansas. He is married to Karen Ball and they have four children, Henry, Ella, Addie, and Clara. Before attending college Von Drehle secured a job as a reporter at the Denver Post. At the age of seventeen he was the youngest sports writer in the paper’s history. He attended the University of Denver, receiving a Bachelor of Arts degree with double honors in English and Philosophy. Von Drehle continued his education at Oxford University, graduating with a Master of Letters in 1985.
After college he became a staff writer for The Miami Herald, receiving the Livingston Award for National Reporting, American Society of Newspaper Editors Distinguished Writing Award, and the American Bar Association Silver Gavel during his tenure at the paper. Von Drehle left The Miami Herald in 1991 to become senior writer and eventually assistant managing editor at The Washington Post. Currently Von Drehle is editor-at-large for TIME, a position he has held since 2007.
Von Drehle is also an author of four books, Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row (1995), Deadlock: The Inside Story of America’s Closest Election (2001), Triangle: The Fire That Changed America (2003), and Rise to Greatness: Abraham Lincoln and American’s Most Perilous Year (2012). Von Drehle has also been a board member of many community organizations, including his current role as a director of the Youth Ambassadors of Kansas City and the Truman Library Institute.
David Von Drehle is an award winning journalist. He is the author of several books including 1985's Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row, the book this collection is based upon. Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row is described as: “Perhaps the finest book ever written on the death penalty” by the Chicago Tribune. The Von Drehle Papers contain all of the research material used to write this book, including correspondence, newspaper clippings, interview notes, law review articles, court appeals, and copies of inmate letters and diaries. It also features newspaper cover stories about the death penalty, including articles written by Von Drehle.
Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row highlights faults in the capital punishment system not only in Florida, but throughout the country. Through in-depth interviews, review of famous cases and over ten years of research, Von Drehle hoped to capture a true picture of death row.
This collection is organized alphabetically by subject. Not all dates in the collection are inclusive. Cases of possible interest involving the death penalty within the Von Drehle Papers include Ted Bundy, William Jent, Ernest Miller, John Spenkelink, Robert Sullivan, and Arthur Goode. The collection also provides an overview of capital punishment in Florida.
The archivist retained the original order of Von Drehle's record keeping scheme. Therefore please note that case files, such as Willie Darden's, also include materials about other court cases involving related subjects or circumstances. Von Drehle also created Florida specific subject files, and then separate general folders on the same topic.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Subject and Genre Headings
Death Penalty; Criminal Justice and Prisons; Von Drehle, David, 1961-; Bundy, Ted-; Darden, Willie Jasper, -1988; Graham, Bob, 1936-; United States. Supreme Court.; Florida. Supreme Court.; NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund.; Capital punishment--Florida.; Death row inmates--Florida--Case studies.; Depositions; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Notes; Transcripts; Files by subject
Container List
- A-Leads to file, 1990-1994; Undated; nam_apap213-1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Abolition Study Commission, ca. 1963-1965; nam_apap213-2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Abolition attempts, 1977; 1979; nam_apap213-3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A.D. Adams - execution, 1989; nam_apap213-4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- A.D. Adams - family, 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- A.D. Adams - litigation, 1984; 1986; 1989; Undated; nam_apap213-6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- A.D. Adams - mitigation, 1986; nam_apap213-7 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- A.D. Adams - mitigation, 1989; 1987; 1991-1993; nam_apap213-8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Adams, James - chronology, Undated; nam_apap213-9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Adams, James - clemency, 1980; 1984; nam_apap213-10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Adams, James - commentary, 1984; nam_apap213-11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Adams, James - execution, 1984; nam_apap213-12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Adams, James - innocence?, 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Adams, James - interviews, Undated; nam_apap213-14 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Adams, James - race, 1984; nam_apap213-15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Alabama - overturn death penalty, 1980; nam_apap213-16 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Antone, Anthony - aftermath, 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-17 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Antone, Anthony - case accounts, 1984; nam_apap213-18 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Antone, Anthony - execution, 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-19 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Antone, Anthony - interviews, 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-20 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Antone, Anthony - litigation/clemency, 1984; nam_apap213-21 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Antone, Anthony - protests, 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-22 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Arango, Carlos, Undated; nam_apap213-23 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Archives - directory, Undated; nam_apap213-24 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Askew, Reubin [Gov], 1972; 1977-1978; Undated; nam_apap213-25 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Attorney crisis, 1982; 1984-1985; 1994; Undated; nam_apap213-26 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Attorney shortages, 1986-1988; 1990-1991; 1994; Undated; nam_apap213-27 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
- Barclay v. Florida, 1982-1983; nam_apap213-28 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Barefoot v. Estelle (& companies), 1982; nam_apap213-29 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Barnard, Craig [Attorney], 1979; 1983; 1987-1989; Undated; nam_apap213-30 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Bertolotti, Anthony, 1990; 2003; nam_apap213-31 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Bibliography, 1982; 1986; 1990-1991; Undated; nam_apap213-32 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Block, Irwin [Attorney], Undated; nam_apap213-33 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Bolender, Bernard, 1982; nam_apap213-34 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Booker, Stephen T., 1983; 1986; 1991; nam_apap213-35 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Booth v. Maryland, 1986; 1990; nam_apap213-36 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Bowers, Bill [death penalty abolitionist], Undated; nam_apap213-37 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Branford, Vernon [D.O.C.], 1984; nam_apap213-38 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Brain research, 1985; Undated; nam_apap213-39 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Brieghton, Dave, 1977-1979; Undated; nam_apap213-40 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Brown, Joseph Green, 1983; 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-41 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Brown v. Florida/Wanwright, 1977; 1980-1983; Undated; nam_apap213-42 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Bundy - 1986, Undated; nam_apap213-43 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Bundy - audio cassettes, Early life/Sheridan Street, Undated; nam_apap213-44 (Cassette 1-3)
- Bundy - audio cassettes, Aspen, Undated; nam_apap213-45 (Cassette 4-6)
- Bundy - audio cassettes, Verdicts, 1979-1980; nam_apap213-46 (Cassette 7-11)
- Bundy - audio cassettes, Execution, Undated; nam_apap213-47 (Cassette 12)
- Bundy - chronologies, 1986; 1989; Undated; nam_apap213-48 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Bundy - clips/media, 1979; 1987; 1989; nam_apap213-49 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Bundy - commentary, 1980; 1989; nam_apap213-50 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Bundy - confessions, 1989-1991; Undated; nam_apap213-51 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Bundy - corpse photo, 1989; 1993; nam_apap213-52 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Bundy - daughter, 1981; nam_apap213-53 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Bundy - demonology, 1987; 1989-1991; Undated; nam_apap213-54 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Bundy - Dobson, 1989-1990; Undated; nam_apap213-55 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Bundy - escape attempt, 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-56 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Bundy - execution, 1989; nam_apap213-57 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Bundy - family, 1989; nam_apap213-58 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Bundy - last appeals, 1988; Undated; nam_apap213-59 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Bundy - last days, 1989; Undated; nam_apap213-60 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Bundy - litigation (folders 1-2 of 11), 1982-1983; 1986-1989; Undated; nam_apap213-61 (Box 1, Folder 59-60)
- Bundy - litigation (folders 3-11 of 11), 1982-1983; 1986-1989; Undated; nam_apap213-62 (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
- Bundy -New York Times, 1986; nam_apap213-63 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Bundy - notes, Undated; nam_apap213-64 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bundy - psychology, 1979; 1988-1991; Undated; nam_apap213-65 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Bundy - Tanner, 1989-1990; Undated; nam_apap213-66 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bundy - victims, 1989; nam_apap213-67 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Bundy - will, Undated; nam_apap213-68 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Butterworth, Bob, 1986; nam_apap213-69 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Carter, Jimmy, 1987; 1990; Undated; nam_apap213-70 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Cary, Susan [Attorney], Undated; nam_apap213-71 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Cases - misc., 1988; 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-72 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- CCR - Capital Collateral Representative, 1985-1989; Undated; nam_apap213-73 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Churches - other religious organizations, 1980-1981; 1983-1985; 1988; 1990; Undated; nam_apap213-74 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Clark, Ramsey, 1971; Undated; nam_apap213-75 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Clearinghouse, 1982; Undated; nam_apap213-76 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Clemency - first 6, 1971; 1976-1977; 1979; nam_apap213-77 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Clemency - general, 1980-1983; 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-78 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Coker v. Georgia, 1976; nam_apap213-79 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Coler, Daniel, 1980; 1982; nam_apap213-80 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Collins, LeRoy [Gov], 1979; nam_apap213-81 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Cooper, Vernon, 1977; 1989-1991; Undated; nam_apap213-82 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Cost studies, 1982; 1987-1988; 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-83 (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
- Court overloads, 1981; 1987-1988; Undated; nam_apap213-84 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Cover stories about the death penalty, including Von Drehle bylines, 1987-1989; 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-85 (Oversized 1)
- Crime rates/fear, 1980; 1982; 1990-1994; Undated; nam_apap213-86 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Darden, Willie - case accounts, 1988; nam_apap213-87 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Darden, Willie - charisma, 1980-1981; 1985; nam_apap213-88 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Darden, Willie - chronology, Undated; nam_apap213-89 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Darden, Willie - close calls, 1985; Undated; nam_apap213-90 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Darden, Willie - commentary, 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-91 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Darden, Willie - execution, 1988; Undated; nam_apap213-92 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Darden, Willie - litigation/clemency, 1976; 1984-1985; 1988; Undated; nam_apap213-93 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Darden, Willie - protests, 1988; Undated; nam_apap213-94 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Darden, Willie - race, 1978; 1988; Undated; nam_apap213-95 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Darden, Willie - victims, Undated; nam_apap213-96 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Darden, Willie - writings, Undated; nam_apap213-97 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Daugherty, Jeffery - execution, 1988; nam_apap213-98 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Death belt, 1985; nam_apap213-99 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Death penalty - analysis of failings, 1985; Undated; nam_apap213-100 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Death penalty - cost, 1988; 1992; Undated; nam_apap213-101 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Death penalty - general commentary, 1962; 1979; 1985-1986; 1988; Undated; nam_apap213-102 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- 18th-19th century death penalty - history, 1897; 1982; 1989; Undated; nam_apap213-103 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- 20th century death penalty- history, 1900-1942; 1964-1971; 1976-1977; 1982-1991; Undated; nam_apap213-104 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Death penalty - national, 1985; 1987-1994; Undated; nam_apap213-105 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Death penalty - international, 1981; 1991-1993; nam_apap213-106 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Death penalty - outlines, 1989; nam_apap213-107 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Death penalty - politics, 1984; 1988; 1990-1994; Undated; nam_apap213-108 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Death penalty - seminars/education, 1983-1984; Undated; nam_apap213-109 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Death penalty - statistics, 1984; 1987-1990; 1992-1994; Undated; nam_apap213-110 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Death Row, Undated; nam_apap213-111 (Video-tape 1)
- Death Row - daily grind, 1967-1971; 1976-1977; 1980-1984; 1988-1989; Undated; nam_apap213-112 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Death Row - Florida, 1980; Undated; nam_apap213-113 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Death Row - inmate protests, 1975-1976; 1978-1980; nam_apap213-114 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Death Row - national, 1976-1979; 1981; 1989; 1992; Undated; nam_apap213-115 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Death Row - rosters/population, 1976-1979; 1981-1984; 1994; Undated; nam_apap213-116 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Death Row - suicides, 1975; 1982-1985; Undated; nam_apap213-117 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Death Row - women, 1977; 1979; 1989-1990; Undated; nam_apap213-118 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Death watch, 1984; 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-119 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Defense tactics - trial, 1981; 1983-1984; 1993; nam_apap213-120 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
- Delay - examples, 1983; 1985; 1988; 1991-1992; nam_apap213-121 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Demps, Benny, 1981-1982; Undated; nam_apap213-122 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Deterrence, 1980; 1983-1984; 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-123 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Dobbert, Ernest - bio/case accounts, 1982; nam_apap213-124 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Dobbert, Ernest - child abuse, 1982; Undated; nam_apap213-125 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Dobbert, Ernest - commentary, 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-126 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Dobbert, Ernest - execution/last hours, 1984; nam_apap213-127 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Dobbert, Ernest - litigation/clemency, 1982; 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-128 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Doherty, Pat [Attorney], 1982; 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-129 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Domestic violence, Undated; nam_apap213-130 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Dougan, Jacob, 1977; 1990; Undated; nam_apap213-131 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Douglas, Howard, 1971; 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-132 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Dugger, Richard [D.O.C.], 1979; 1982; 1984-1986; Undated; nam_apap213-133 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Durocher, Michael - voluntary execution, 1993; nam_apap213-134 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Electric chair, 1979; 1990; 1992; Undated; nam_apap213-135 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Electrocution - effects/procedures, 1983; 1990; Undated; nam_apap213-136 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
- Eleventh Circuit - judges, 1990-1991; nam_apap213-137 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Emund v. Florida/Tison v. Arizona, 1981-1982; 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-138 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Escapes, 1980; 1982-1983; Undated; nam_apap213-139 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Executions - broadcasts/interviews, 1977; 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-140 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Executions - chronologies, 1990; Undated; nam_apap213-141 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Execution - technical/procedure, 1973; 1979; 1984-1989; 1990-1992; Undated; nam_apap213-142 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Famous cases, 1985; Undated; nam_apap213-143 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Farmer, Millard [Attorney], Undated; nam_apap213-144 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Feamster, Tom, Undated; nam_apap213-145 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Fins, Deborah [Attorney], Undated; nam_apap213-146 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Fleming, Myron, Undated; nam_apap213-147 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- FL Governor's race '86, 1985-1986; nam_apap213-148 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- FL Governor's Select Committee, 1972; Undated; nam_apap213-149 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Florida - corrections, 1980; 1982-1983; 1986; 1989-1990; Undated; nam_apap213-150 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Florida - legislation, 1967; 1972; 1980; Undated; nam_apap213-151 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Florida - media coverage, 1985; 1990; nam_apap213-152 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Florida - overview, 1981; 1983; 1985; Undated; nam_apap213-153 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Florida - rape provision, 1981-1982; Undated; nam_apap213-154 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Florida -regional differences, 1979; 1982; 1986; nam_apap213-155 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Florida State Prison, 1980-1983; 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-156 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Florida Supreme Court - cases, 1980-1981; 1989-1990; 1994; Undated; nam_apap213-157 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Florida Supreme Court - justices, 1979; 1985-1988; Undated; nam_apap213-158 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Florida Supreme Court - scene analysis, 1983; 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-159 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Ford, Alvin, 1981-1982; 1984-1986; Undated; nam_apap213-160 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Francis v. Resweber, 1946; nam_apap213-161 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Francois, Marvin - execution, 1985; Undated; nam_apap213-162 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Funchess, David - case accounts, 1979; Undated; nam_apap213-163 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Funchess, David - execution, 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-164 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Funchess, David - PTSD, 1986; 1988; 1991; 1993; Undated; nam_apap213-165 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Furman v. Georgia, 1971-1972; 1992; Undated; nam_apap213-166 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Furman - reaction, 1972-1973; Undated; nam_apap213-167 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Furman - survivors, Undated; nam_apap213-168 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Gardner v. Florida, 1976; nam_apap213-169 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Georgieff, George [Attorney], 1963; 1967; 1974; 1981; Undated; nam_apap213-170 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Gibson, Robin, Undated; nam_apap213-171 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Gilmore, Gary - reaction, 1976-1977; nam_apap213-172 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Golstein, Steve, Undated; nam_apap213-173 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Goode - case accounts, 1978; Undated; nam_apap213-174 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Goode - commentary, 1982; 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-175 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Goode - description/interviews, 1977-1980; 1982-1984; Undated; nam_apap213-176 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Goode - execution, 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-177 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Goode - family, 1982; 1984; 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-178 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Goode - inmate hatred, 1977; Undated; nam_apap213-179 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Goode - last hours, 1984; nam_apap213-180 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Goode - litigation/clemency, 1982-1984; Undated; nam_apap213-181 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Goode - petitions, 1983; Undated; nam_apap213-182 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Goode - sanity, 1977-1980; Undated; nam_apap213-183 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Graham, Bob [Gov], 1977; 1979-1986; 1989; Undated; nam_apap213-184 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Gregg v. Georgia, 1975; 1980; Undated; nam_apap213-185 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Guided discretion - analysis, 1980; Undated; nam_apap213-186 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Habeas reform, 1985-1986; 1988; 1990-1991; Undated; nam_apap213-187 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
- Hall, Freddie Lee/Ruffin, Mark, 1982; nam_apap213-188 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Hallman, Clifford, 1977; nam_apap213-189 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Hamblen, James, 1988; 1990; Undated; nam_apap213-190 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Harris, Robert, 1979; 1982; 1989-1990; Undated; nam_apap213-191 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Harris, Robert - litigation/habeas corpus, 1990; Undated; nam_apap213-192 (Box 4, Folder 27-29)
- Harrison, Baya [Attorney], ca.1991-1986; Undated; nam_apap213-193 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Henry, James - case accounts, Undated; nam_apap213-194 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Henry, James - execution, 1984; nam_apap213-195 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Henry, James - race, 1984; nam_apap213-196 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Henry, James - victim, 1979; nam_apap213-197 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Hitchcock v. Dugger, 1978; 1983; 1986; 1991; Undated; nam_apap213-198 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Holdman, Scharlette, 1979; 1981-1984; 1988-1989; Undated; nam_apap213-199 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- House Select Committee, 1972; Undated; nam_apap213-200 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Hoy, Darrell, 1980; nam_apap213-201 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Hudson, Olliff [Judge], 1975; 1981; 1983; Undated; nam_apap213-202 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Hull, Steve, ca. 1991-1986; Undated; nam_apap213-203 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Ingle, Joe, Undated; nam_apap213-204 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Innocence, 1987; 1989; 1992-1993; Undated; nam_apap213-205 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Jent/Miller - aftermath, 1989; Undated; nam_apap213-206 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Jent/Miller - appeals, 1981-1983; 1986-1987; Undated; nam_apap213-207 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Jent/Miller - Armstrong, 1979; 1987; nam_apap213-208 (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
- Jent/Miller - assorted police, 1978-1979; 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-209 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Jent/Miller - autopsies, 1979; 1983; 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-210 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Jent/Miller - Carroll, 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-211 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Jent/Miller - case (folder 1 of 3), 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-212 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Jent/Miller - case (folder 2-3 of 3), 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-213 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- Jent/Miller - clemency, 1983; nam_apap213-214 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Jent/ Miller - chronologies, 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-215 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Jent/ Miller - clips/media, 1979-1980; 1983-1988; Undated; nam_apap213-216 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Jent/ Miller - cops, 1979-1980; 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-217 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Jent/Miller - Dalton, 1985-1988; Undated; nam_apap213-218 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Jent/Miller - Dodd, 1986-1987; Undated; nam_apap213-219 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Jent/Miller - Elmer/Tina, 1980; 1983-1984; Undated; nam_apap213-220 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
- Jent/Miller - Fitzgerald, 1979-1980; 1986-1987; Undated; nam_apap213-221 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
- Jent/Miller - Fritts, 1987; nam_apap213-222 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Jent/Miller - Frye, 1979; 1981; 1986-1987; Undated; nam_apap213-223 (Box 5, Folder 14-16)
- Jent/Miller - Hubbard, 1979; 1986-1987; Undated; nam_apap213-224 (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
- Jent/Miller - inmate testimony, 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-225 (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
- Jent/Miller - Morris McDonald, 1987; Undated; nam_apap213-226 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Jent/Miller - motions, 1987; nam_apap213-227 (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
- Jent/Miller - new trial battles, 1988; nam_apap213-228 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Jent/Miller - notes, Undated; nam_apap213-229 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Jent/Miller - own letters, 1982; nam_apap213-230 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Jent/Miller - police investigation, 1979-1980; nam_apap213-231 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Jent/Miller - release, 1988; Undated; nam_apap213-232 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Jent/Miller - sources, 1985; 1987-1988; Undated; nam_apap213-233 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Jent/Miller - Suzie (Ruby) letters, 1985; Undated; nam_apap213-234 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Jent/Miller - Tricaine/Bennett, 1979; 1986; Undated; nam_apap213-235 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
- Justice, Undated; nam_apap213-236 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Juveniles, 1986-1987; 1989; 1990; nam_apap213-237 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- In re: Kemmler, 1889; nam_apap213-238 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Kendall, David [Attorney], 1990; Undated; nam_apap213-239 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Kennedy, Edward F., 1992; nam_apap213-240 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Knight, Thomas (Askari Muhammad), 1980; 1982; 1984; Undated; nam_apap213-241 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Lambrix, Michael, 1988; 1991-1992; Undated; nam_apap213-242 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Last meals, 1985; Undated; nam_apap213-243 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Legal Defense Fund, 1990; nam_apap213-244 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Legal Defense Fund - strategy, 1977; nam_apap213-245 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
- Lethal Injection, 1979; 1991; nam_apap213-246 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Lewis, Dorothy O., 1985; 1991-1992; nam_apap213-247 (Box 6, Folder 20)